Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- WPFW 89.3 FM Archived Website, Jul 16, 2011- ongoing; WPFW (Radio station: Washington, D.C.)
  WPFW is the fifth station of Pacifica Radio, a progressive network founded in 1949 by maverick broadcaster Lewis Hill. WPFW was established in 1977 in Washington DC.
  Alternative radio and broadcasting |z Washington, D.C.
- YIVO Institute for Jewish Research Archived Website, Apr 2, 2012- ongoing; Yivo Institute for Jewish Research.
  YIVO Institute for Jewish Research, was founded in Vilna, Poland, in 1925 and relocated to New York City in 1940. The YIVO Archives holds over 24 million documents, photographs, recordings, posters, films, videotapes, and items of ephemera and YIVO Library holds over 385,000 books and periodicals in twelve major languages. Their mission is to preserve, study and teach the cultural history of Jewish life throughout Eastern Europe, Germany and Russia. Their educational and public outreach programs concentrate on all aspects of this 1000-year history and its continuing influence in America. Many public programs focus on progressive and Jewish movements. YIVO is located at the Center for Jewish History. The website contains information on their library and archives, publications, and programming listings.
  Jews |x History.; Judaism and communism.; Yiddishkeit.
- Young Communist League USA Archived Website, Aug 10, 2009- ongoing; Young Communist League of the U.S.
  The Young Communist League, USA is a multi-racial, working-class organization made up of youth who believe we can build a better world. We come from a variety of backgrounds, just like the young people of our country: we are employed and unemployed workers, we are high school and college students, we are Black, white, Latino, Asian, and Native American, we are gay and straight, we are women and men. The YCL is associated with the Communist Party of the United States of America.
  Communism |z United States.; Socialism and youth |z United States.; Youth movements |z United States.
- Young Democratic Socialists Archived Website, Nov 25, 2008- ongoing; Young Democratic Socialists.
  Young Democratic Socialists (YDS) is the youth affiliate of the Democratic Socialists of America, founded in 1983. YDS organizes on college campuses to fight for the immediate needs of workers and students, while building the capacity to fight for more radical and structural changes in the long term. The website contains information on their student chapters, their coordinating committee, current platforms, which include student debt relief and labor solidarity, news and multimedia, and their blog, the Activist.
  Democratic Socialists of America.; Socialism and youth |z United States.
- Young People's Socialist League Archived Website, Aug 10, 2009-Nov 13, 2010; Young People's Socialist League.
  The Young People's Socialist League (YPSL), established in 1913, is the youth affiliate of the Socialist Party, USA. The website contains organizing tools, their constitution and principles, and a message board. The site became defunct in 2010.
  Socialist Party (U.S.).; Socialism and youth |z United States.
- Young People's Socialist League Reunion Archived Website, Sep 28, 2007-May 8, 2008; Young People's Socialist League Reunion.
  This website was formed in connection with a 2007 reunion in New York City of members of the Young People's Socialist League. The YPSL, as it was commonly known, was the youth group affiliated with the Socialist Party (U.S.) Many of its members allied themselves with the views of Leon Trotsky.
  Socialist Party (U.S.).; Socialism and youth |z United States.; Trotskyism |z United States.
- Young People For Archived Website, Nov 6, 2011- ongoing; People For the American Way Foundation
  Young People For (YP4), founded in 2004 by the People For the American Way Foundation, is a strategic-long term leadership initiative to invest in the next generation of leaders and build a long-term national network for young progressives. YP4 serves young adults who are emerging leaders in their communities, and works with them to create change in their communities while empowering the newest generations of skilled, progressive leaders who will lead with progressive values, make progress in their communities and create sustainable change over the long term. They offer resources, guidance and a wide variety of ongoing opportunities for young leaders to connect with other progressive leaders and organizations, plan and execute projects of their choosing, and learn valuable leadership, communication, organizing, collaboration and advocacy skills.
  Leadership--Study and teaching (Higher)--United States.
- Youth for International Socialism Archived Website, Dec 9, 2008-Jan 9, 2013; Youth for International Socialism.
  Youth for International Socialism was a group of workers and youth that fight for the end of capitalism, and for democratic socialism, as explained by the ideas of Marxism. They stood for the right to strike, union representation, and collective bargaining; for trade union democracy; for a mass party of labor to power; full employment and housing; a living wage for all; free, quality health care for all; free, quality education for all; for the immediate and unconditional legalization of all undocumented immigrants; equal rights for all; a socialized plan of production for agriculture and natural resources; action to protect the environment; nationalization of the commanding heights of the economy; and socialist internationalism. The website contains an FAQ, a message board, and their platform.
  Communism.; Socialism and youth.; Trotskyism.
- Zeitgeist Movement Archived Website, Apr 25, 2012- ongoing; Zeitgeist Movement
  The Zeitgeist Movement, founded 2008, is a sustainability advocacy organization which conducts community based activism and awareness actions through a network of global/regional chapters, project teams, annual events, media and charity work. The movement campaigns against the "monetary-market" economy which they argue should be replaced with a resource-based economy. The website contains information on their annual ZDay, an FAQ, action alerts, radio show, multimedia, and a blog.
  Sustainable development.
- Z Net Archived Website, Mar 9, 2010- ongoing; Z Communications.
  ZNet is an online progressive magazine and community of alternative news, opinions, discussion forums, and resources from ZNet. ZNet’s magazine, Z Magazine, created in 1987, is a radical print and online periodical dedicated to resisting injustice, eliminating repression, and creating liberty. It addresses international relations, ecology, economics, gender, race, culture, politics, and other topics. Z Communications acts as a portal to different aspects of ZNet, which focuses on a huge scope of issues and variety of media.
  United States |x Politics and government.; United States |x Social conditions.
- Zuccotti Park Press Archived Website, Nov 27, 2012- ongoing; Zuccotti Park Press
  Zuccotti Park Press is the website for the Occupy Wall Street Movement’s pamphlet series, taking the name from the park where the protest took place in fall 2011. The website features digital versions of their pamphlets.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Pamphlet series (New York, N.Y.).